

■ me@jakelyell.dev | □ 0447497539 | ♥ Perth, WA

% jakelyell.dev | in Jake Lyell | ♠ JakeLDev

Computer Science and Data Science student with fundamental knowledge of software design and development. Committed to working as a collaborative and positive team member, striving to utilize my knowledge and expertise for optimal results. Possesses the analytical, technical, and programming skills required to thrive as a Software Engineer.

Education

University of Western Australia

Perth

Bachelor of Science, Double Major in Computer Science and Data Science GPA: 5.636 | WAM: 71 Feb 2019 - Jun 2022

Work Experience

St Vincent de Paul WA

Perth

Web Developer

Nov 2021 – Present

- Developing a new intranet system for Vinnies WA. To be used across 52 stores, warehouse depos, and head office staff. This private site hosts all internal documents, templates and forms for Vinnies WA, and is to be used by hundreds of staff and volunteers.
- · Working to meet client deadlines.
- Creating a consistent look and feel across the website by enforcing uniform formatting and layout.
- Trained employees on how to use the new site efficiently.

QFin UWA UWA, Perth

Executive Director of Trading

Dec 2021 - Present

- Creating and running projects for 2022's Quantitative Finance Trading Team. These projects are focused around core mathematical and algorithmic theories.
- Organizing and running trading-based events and workshops. Including a Hackathon for other Computer Science students to participate in an Algorithmic Trading Competition.
- Building a website and an algorithm back testing framework for use by QFin.

Coders for Causes UWA

UWA, Perth

Volunteer Web Developer

Nov 2021 – Present

- · Creating a Responsive Vue.js Web Application for WAIS to help visualize the performance of pole vaulters in training.
- Working closely with our client to ensure a satisfactory product is delivered.
- · Participating effectively in the team-based environment. Working closely with my team members to complete GitHub issues

Projects

Visualizing Crime Data for WA Police Force

Python, Pandas, PyQt5, GIS

Created an interactive Python application for the Data Science and Analytics Division of the WA Police Force to visualize crime data trends on an interactive heat map of Western Australia. Performed a team leadership role, ensuring that deliverables were completed on time, and team resources were managed effectively.

Momentum Trading Algorithm

Python, TA-Lib, Pandas

Created a set of Python algorithms to trade cryptocurrencies, based around the Quantitative Trading strategy of "Momentum Trading". Performed significant testing to determine the best combination of algorithm and parameters to produce a consistently well performing algorithm.

QFin Organization Website

React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Creating a React.js Web Application to showcase the QFin UWA Club. The site features past and future projects and events. The site also showcases the Exec Team and our Sponsors

gfinuwa.com

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java **Frameworks and Libraries:** Pandas, NumPy, React.js, Vue.js

Software: Git/GitHub, Linux, Visual Studio Code, Docker

Relavent Coursework: Project Management, Organisational Behaviour, Machine Learning, Agile Development